xdrive.com 2005-06-22

# Xdrive : Secure Online Storage

Xdrive, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.xdrive.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users’ privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact Xdrive's Customer Support group by e-mail at [support@xdrive.com](mailto:support@xdrive.com). If they do not receive acknowledgment of their inquiry or their inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, they should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process (<http://truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site.

Simply put, we are committed to providing you with the best service available online or elsewhere.

This policy explains:

* * *

  * What Xdrive is and why your information is needed
  * What personal information is collected from you
  * What cookies are and how they are used
  * How your information is used
  * Who is collecting your information
  * With whom your information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information
  * How you can access, update or delete your information
  * The security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information
  * How Xdrive uses contact information that you might provide when "Sending a File" or "Sharing a Folder"
  * What else you should know about your online privacy
  * Additional Information
  * Other Resources

* * *

## What is Xdrive and why is my information needed?

Xdrive provides customers with online storage space which can be used to store, share, access, and protect important files. Xdrive is web based, and we require, at a minimum, a first name, last name, password, and valid e-mail address. 

## What personal information does Xdrive collect from me?

Xdrive collects personal information upon registration. During registration for a free account , Xdrive typically will ask for your name and e-mail address. When upgrading to a premium paid account, Xdrive will ask for your credit card information in order to provide you uninterrupted service. Please note that the more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once registered, you are part of the Xdrive community, a customer account is created, and you can take full advantage of Xdrive's services.

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including immediately following the registration process, when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by Xdrive, and when you report a problem with the service or with your account. If you contact Xdrive we will keep a record of that correspondence. In addition, Xdrive occasionally asks registered users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. A link is included to this Privacy Policy wherever Xdrive collects personal information.

Xdrive customers use our service to store files and folders (data). Xdrive will not review, share, distribute, print, or reference any such data except as outlined in the Terms of Service or as may be required by law.

## What are cookies and how does Xdrive use them?

In order to provide a personalized service, Xdrive uses cookies to store some information about your account. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server that is stored on your computer's hard drive. Xdrive uses both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. These cookies are not tied to your personally identifiable information.

Generally, we use cookies:

  * To establish an authenticated session with the service when you login to your Xdrive account using our web interface. When you use Xdrive's web interface to access your account, logging in will require that you accept a session ID cookie. When you close your web browser, the session ID cookie will terminate.
  * To remember some of your basic account preferences in order to deliver a better, more personalized service. A persistent cookie may be set when you register, "Sign In," or use the Xdrive web interface to record certain application settings and other preferences.

Xdrive may also record your IP address for system administration, monitoring, and fraud prevention purposes. IP Addresses are not linked or cross-referenced with any personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Xdrive only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies.

## How does Xdrive use my information?

Xdrive does not provide any of your personal information to third parties except as outlined in this privacy policy. We do not sell or give access to our customer e-mail list or other customer profile information to anyone except as outlined.

Xdrive does research on customer demographics and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, or from surveys. This information is tracked using log files, tracking pixels and database history tables. We do this to better understand and serve our customers. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis.

## Who is collecting information?

When you access Xdrive and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Xdrive alone. We also make use of the Omniture service ([http://www.omniture.com](http://www.omniture.com/)) to provide basic reporting on web site visitors and usage patterns. Omniture does NOT capture any information that can personally identify any of Xdrive's customers or visitors. Omniture is compliant with the Platform for Privacy Preferences Project (P3P), as developed by the World Wide Web Consortium.

## With whom does Xdrive share my information?

Xdrive will not disclose any of your personal information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see our Terms of Service for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.

  * **Data in the Aggregate** : Xdrive may disclose aggregated statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.
  * **Special Circumstances:** Xdrive may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Xdrive's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Xdrive's rights or property, other Xdrive users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Xdrive may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.
  * **Service Providers:** When you sign up for an Xdrive premium paid service, we will encrypt the data and pass relevant information to a third party credit card processing company. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.
  * **Third Party Retail Distributors:** Should you signup for Xdrive through one of our third party retail distributors, Xdrive may disclose your email address to that specific third party retail distributor.

## What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?

Xdrive may, from time to time, e-mail you regarding our products and services. Only Xdrive or agents working under confidentiality agreements on behalf of Xdrive will send you such e-mail. Customers who do not wish to receive these announcements may opt-out of receiving these communications by sending an e-mail to [unsubscribe@xdrive.com](mailto:unsubscribe@xdrive.com). All announcements sent by Xdrive also include unsubscribe instructions.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to access your Xdrive via the web interface.

Xdrive does not sell or provide access to customer information to anyone, unless you happen to sign up for an account through a third-party affiliate, in which case that affiliate also has your e-mail address. If there is any other exception to this policy, we will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer.

## What is Xdrive's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personal information?

You can edit your Xdrive account information at any time by accessing your account using our web interface (your profile information can be modified by accessing the "My Profile" page once you are logged in). If you have forgotten your password, please visit our Customer Support Center to request a new one.

Your Xdrive account can be easily deleted or deactivated at anytime. Doing so will result in losing access to most functions and services provided by Xdrive, including your Xdrive account and any files stored in it. Please visit our Customer Support Center for instructions about deleting or deactivating your Xdrive account. Residual account information remains archived within our records.

## What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

When you register for an Xdrive account, the signup page may ask you for sensitive information (such as your credit card number). Information collected when you register is encrypted and is protected with industry standard SSL encryption. While on a secure page, such as our signup page, the padlock icon on the bottom of most Web browsers becomes locked.

Your Xdrive account information and Xdrive customer profile are password-protected so that you, and only you, have access to this personal information. You may edit your Xdrive account information by logging into our web interface using your Xdrive username and password.

We require that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Xdrive will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. Also remember to sign out of your Xdrive account and close your browser window when you finish your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information or files if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

As a global company, Xdrive has international sites and users all over the world. When you give Xdrive personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered it. Whenever Xdrive handles personal information as described above, regardless of where it occurs, Xdrive takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Xdrive cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or while using the service, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

## What does Xdrive do with contact information that I might provide when sharing files or folders?

When you use Xdrive to "Send a File" or "Share a Folder" with someone, you normally enter that person's e-mail address into the system so that a message can be sent informing him or her of the share. Xdrive treats any contact information that you enter while using the service with the same respect and confidentiality as your own information. E-mail addresses that you enter when using Xdrive to share information are not sold or made available to any 3rd parties.

When you use Xdrive's "Send a File" feature, you can elect to have the system send a notification message on your behalf by entering the e-mail address(es) of the person(s) with whom you want to share the file. If you prefer, you can instead generate a web link to the file, which can be sent as part of your own message. Send a File notification messages sent by Xdrive are one-time only messages with the sole intent of notifying the recipient of the shared file.

Using Xdrive's "Share a Folder" feature requires that the person you are sharing with have an Xdrive account to access the folder. If the person you are sharing with does not already have an Xdrive account, a free sharing account will be created for that person when you share the folder. Xdrive will automatically send an e-mail inviting the person to activate their free account so they can access the folder you have shared. To activate, the sharing account holder need only enter their first and last name (which is used strictly for Customer Support purposes and to personalize the Xdrive experience) and choose a password. The same Privacy Policy in effect for paying subscribers also applies to Xdrive Free accounts, except that ads may be served to free accounts.

## What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Xdrive is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site.

Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible online.

## Additional Information

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [privacy@xdrive.com](mailto:privacy@xdrive.com). For additional information on contacting Xdrive, please click here.

## Other Resources

  * [Electronic Frontier Foundation](http://www.eff.org/) \- a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online.
  * [Electronic Privacy Information Center](http://epic.org/) \- established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. 
  * [Privacy Issues Page](http://www.cdt.org/privacy/) \- from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT).
  * [The EPIC Cookies Page](http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/) \- definitions, links, and news. 
  * [How to Protect Your Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission
